(Q21（单选）) TUTOR: OK, Jim. You wanted to see me about your textile design project.
JIM: That's right. I've been looking at how a range of natural dyes can be used to colour fabrics like cotton and wool.
TUTOR: Why did you choose that topic?
[Q21干扰项A：听转折] JIM: Well, I got a lot of useful ideas from the museum, you know, at that exhibition of textiles.
[Q21答案句C：听转折] But I've always been interested in anything to do with colour. Years ago, I went to a carpet shop with my parents when we were on holiday in Turkey, and I remember all the amazing colours.
TUTOR: They might not all have been natural dyes.
[Q21干扰项B： 是在决定follow it up 之后才找来的书。] JIM: Maybe not, but for the project I decided to follow it up. And I found a great book about a botanic garden in California that specialises in plants used for dyes.
(Q22) TUTOR: OK. So, in your project, you had to include a practical investigation.
JIM: Yeah. At first I couldn't decide on my variables. I was going to just look at one type of fibre for example, like cotton ...
TUTOR: ... and see how different types of dyes affected it?
JIM: Yes. Then I decided to include others as well, so I looked at cotton and wool and nylon.
TUTOR: With just one type of dye?
[Q22答案句：既提到了one dye, one fibre, 最后确认 都是好几种] JIM: Various types, including some that weren't natural, for comparison.
TUTOR: OK.
(Q23) [Q23干扰项B： 网站有supply，不代表 widely available，偷换概念] JIM: So, I did the experiments last week. I used some ready-made natural dyes, I found a website which supplied them, they came in just a few days, but I also made some of my own.
TUTOR: That must have taken quite a bit of time.
[Q23答案句A：原本以为只要 a teaspoon] JIM: Yes, I'd thought it'd just be a matter of a teaspoon or so of dye, and actually that wasn't the case at all. Like I was using one vegetable, beetroot, for a red dye, and I had to chop up a whole pile of it.
[Q23干扰项C： 费时间的是切东西，不是选项说的 leave the fabric in the dye] So it all took longer than I'd expected.
(Q24) TUTOR: One possibility is to use food colourings.
JIM: I did use one. That was a yellow dye, an artificial one.
TUTOR: Tartrazine?
[Q24答案句B：wash之后，color就 wash away, 🟰 not a permanent dye] JIM: Yeah. I used it on cotton first. It came out a great colour, but when I rinsed the material, the colour just washed away.
[Q24干扰项C： nylon， 想用。 Jim自己排除： I abandon] I'd been going to try it out on nylon, but I abandoned that idea.
TUTOR: Were you worried about health issues?
JIM: I'd thought if it's a legal food colouring, it must be safe. Jim：
[Q24干扰项A： 有过敏反应， 本身没问题，但不是Jim的problem。 这句话是导师说的。 题干说Jim， 就听Jim说的内容] TUTOR: Well, it can occasionally cause allergic reactions, I believe.
(Q25（Matching）) TUTOR: So what natural dyes did you look at?
JIM: Well, one was turmeric. The colour's great, it's a really strong yellow. It's generally used in dishes like curry.
[Q25答案句： not permanent = not long-lasting] TUTOR: It's meant to be quite good for your health when eaten, but you might find it's not permanent when it's used as a dye - a few washes, and it's gone.
(Q26) [Q26答案句：F 颜色unexpected， 手变red, 羊毛变 watery cream， + 态度 disappointed = unexpected] JIM: Right. I used beetroot as a dye for wool. When I chop up beetroot to eat I always end up with bright red hands, but the wool ended up just a sort of watery cream shade. Disappointing.
(Q27) TUTOR: There's a natural dye called Tyrian purple. Have you heard of that?
[Q27干扰项A： expensive？ 只说过去身份显赫的用，不代表现在还 expensive] JIM: Yes. It comes from a shellfish, and it was worn in ancient times but only by important people as it was so rare. I didn't use it.
[Q27答案句H： 有人manage to得到了一些， = not generally available] TUTOR: It fell out of use centuries ago, though one researcher managed to get hold of some recently. But that shade of purple can be produced by chemical dyes nowadays.
(Q28) Did you use any black dyes?
JIM: Logwood. That was quite complicated. I had to prepare the fabric so the dye would take.
TUTOR: I hope you were careful to wear gloves.
JIM: Yes. I know the danger with that dye.
[Q28答案句D： poisonous 解释型] TUTOR: Good. It can be extremely dangerous if it's ingested.
(Q29) Now, presumably you had a look at an insect-based dye? Like cochineal, for example?
[Q29干扰项H： 提到了not available, 只是这个地方not available, 不代表选项中说的generally] JIM: Yes. I didn't actually make that, I didn't have time to start crushing up insects to get the red colour and anyway they're not available here, but I managed to get the dye quite easily from a website.
[Q29答案句A： It is expensive.] But 【it cost a fortune】. I can see why it's generally just used in cooking, and in small quantities.
TUTOR: Yes, it's very effective, but that's precisely why it's not used as a dye.
(Q30) JIM: I also read about using metal oxide. Apparently you can allow iron to rust while it's in contact with the fabric, and that colours it.
[Q30答案句E：It can damage the fabric, damage = affect] TUTOR: Yes, that works well for dying cotton. But you have to be careful as the metal 【can actually affect the fabric】 and so you can't expect to get a lot of wear out of fabrics treated in this way.
[Q30干扰项F： unexpected， 颜色subtle不代表就是unexpected] And the colours are quite subtle, not everyone likes them. Anyway, it looks as if you've done a lot of work ...